hello and welcome to the 18th tutorial
on how to program a gript 2 in this
tutorial I'm going to show you about a
new command called on
wall so in this tutorial I'm going to be
using a weapon but you can also use this
command in a
NPC so let's add client side
and function on player
chats
if the player says the word Mouse then
this is what's going to
happen it's going to go to the function
called on timeouts which we're going to
add
here and at the bottom we can add sleep
0.1 on timeout if we want to Loop it or
because it's an on timeout function we
can just
add set timer 0.1 set timer will always
go to on time the function on timeout if
it exists after how many seconds is in
here okay so in it let's add
if on
wall on wall Mouse X Mouse
y then
do
this player. chat is equal
to on a blocking
tile
else player. chat is equal to not on a
blocking
tile oh okay so I'm going to save this
now since I have the weapon already I'm
just going to type
Mouse and it's just keep going to say
not on a blocking tile but I'm going
to add a title in a
second like let's say a
bush bush is block right so when I put
my mouse on it it's going to say on a
blocking tile and when I take it off
it's not on a blocking tile blocking
tiles are tiles that you can't walk
through on whatever tille set you're
using so that's pretty useful because
you can do things like make NPCs that
don't walk through walls like let's say
you want to make an AI that doesn't walk
through walls you can do that with that
now the mouse X is the x value that your
mouse is on this is by tiles and the
mouse Y is going down the Y AIS that
your mouse is on so Mouse X which is the
first parameter is the X and the second
is the
Y so we can put any variable here like
we could put one if we wanted to that's
not a variable but it's a number so now
if if the tiles um 5 comma 5 are
blocking then it's going to say that or
if it's not then it's going to say this
but since we know that it's not blocking
it's just going to say that anyway we're
just going to put Mouse we can oh yeah
we can also put something like this
player X comma player
doy that'll work we can put this.x
this.y anything like
that let's have to say mouse first and
since you know the players X and Y is
actually at the top left corner of them
so technically you're on the tile if we
want to take that away you know make it
to the center of the player we would add
plus
1.5 and plus 1.5 after them I'm not sure
if this is exactly the center but it's
about so you'll see that nowhere we walk
around it because the center of the
player isn't touching it but now if we
move ourselves
like if we do
this it'll see that we're on a blocking
tile well anyway that's it for this
tutorial actually no I'm going to teach
you one more thing it's called how to
make it's called random and it makes
things random
let's just change the NPC to be like
this
random and then in the NPC let's
add actually why am I doing this I don't
even need the on timeout this
time let's add this dot is random a new
MP a new
variable is equal to
int random 0 comma
9 so then player. chat is equal to this
uh Is
Random so what this is going to do is
when you say the word random it's going
to make this do random a new variable
equal to any number between 0 and
9 and after this you can do things like
if this. random is equal to one then
make it say this or whatever but we're
going to do this so when we cck apply it
says random we get zero let's say random
again we
get we get five again we get one again
we get nine so any number between zero
and N is going to get a random number
from those anyway that concludes this
tutorial and I hope you have a better
understanding on on wall and understand
what how to make things random anyway
that's it for this tutorial and I'll see
you later